Well? How's the coin search going?
Actually, your sister came by recently.
She was looking for you.
Oh... And he was with her.
I was sure that you had told them about me.
I wouldn't do that. I'm neutral here.
All I want is for you to gather coins.
As thanks, I will make your wishes come true.
That's it.
Many people have died for this.
That's not my fault.
Each person is responsible
for how they use their power.
I am really impressed though.
You all are truly amazing!
The way you use your powers,
the powers you seek!
They're all so very unique,
far more so than I imagined!
Even your sister, a normal person
with no special powers--
she got everyone out of that terrible mess!
And what an amazing approach!
If I kill you, this pointless
conflict would end, wouldn't it?
Maybe so. In my current form,
I'm just a human, like you.
It's possible that the conflict would end.
But even if you do, nobody can stop
the things that have already happened.
The flames are dying down.
Shuichi, can you smell anyone following us?
Sorry, I can't be sure with all the smoke...
But I think we lost them.
Okay.
How many died? It doesn't feel real.
I don't want you to carry
the burden of any more crimes.
I said that, but I still feel...
We can't go any further.
Traveling over this mountain
is more difficult than I expected,
and the time we took fighting
them has put us off schedule.
Plus...
I disagree.
Clair!
I don't know exactly how effective
the oleander's poison is.
If some of them managed to survive...
...they've seen our faces.
We've got to gather 100 coins
and put an end to this.
I know that.
But I feel like the things that happened today
are way more than all
of us can deal with at once.
You guys...
We'll pick another route and head home.
It's no good, I can't get through to Ikeuchi.
Maybe he's not out of the mountains yet.
Or...
That's all for today. I'll be in touch.
If anyone did survive, they're going
to hold a strong grudge against us.
Be very careful, everyone.
I'm responsible for this.
How could it have happened?
Other groups might turn into monsters,
but I wanted to see things
through the way I am, as a human.
Humans live by ideals and
will not give in to their vulgar urges--
I wanted to declare this to everyone.
But my own ideals lead us
to that foolish bloodbath!
Even Ikeuchi...
Leader...
Your devotion to your ideals
is a beautiful and precious thing.
I don't care what anyone says--
I'll always trust you.
Would you like me to heat this up?
No... It's not right for me
to rely on your affection like this.
Your shift is starting. Go.
Okay.
Put something cold on it, Isao.
Your face is pretty messed up.
Thanks.
I'm sorry... Yota...
I... I didn't want to do that.
Killing people...
Don't cry. You stood up and defended us.
Unlike me...
How did she think of something so terrible?
It's scary...
There's something wrong with Shuichi, too.
He's been weird right from the start.
He said he was the only student
at Yamada Cram School--
But that can't be true!
Yeah, they are strange.
How... How can they be so calm?
It's as though this
isn't the first time they've...
Hey... Do you think everyone
in that group is dead?
I don't know. But we didn't
have any other choice.
If we hadn't done it, we'd be dead.
It's not your fa--
That's not what I mean!
They saw our faces, right?
If one of them is alive,
we'll always be living in fear.
So...
When I thought about our group,
I realized it'd be better
if the other group was all dead.
Pretty messed up, huh?
I'm sorry. It's because
I got you wrapped up in all this.
No... I think this is my will.
Huh?
You know, right? How my memory
of the time I got my powers has gaps?
Even if it was Elena that
made me take that medicine,
I was the one that chose to turn into a costume.
I feel like I need to use that power to fight,
and that feeling keeps
getting stronger and stronger.
You mean... with Elena?
I don't know. Sometimes it feels
that way, sometimes it doesn't.
I need to find the answer myself.
Once I do, I feel like I'll truly
become one with you, for the first time!
Shuichi... Do you want to go...
hang out somewhere tomorrow?
Huh?
We could go see that movie you mentioned.
No, we shouldn't be going
anywhere people will see us right now.
All right, why don't we rent a movie
and watch it at my place?
After that, we can... fool around.
No! Where did that come from?!
Why not? You did it with that helmet girl!
No I didn't! That was...
I think that was her way of showing she cared.
The next day, I went to school,
just like always.
So, she goes to our school, huh?
So... If, uh...
What if someone had already gathered 100 coins?
What do you think they'd wish for?
I don't know.
At first, I thought everyone would
simply want all their desires fulfilled,
like that group yesterday.
Now... If it was me,
I don't think I'd use them that way.
Is that what you wanted to talk about?
Oh, yeah. Sorry. I didn't have
anything to talk about, really.
I'm just scared from yesterday.
We should pretend we don't
know each other here, for now.
Huh?
We can't be sure there aren't
people from that group here.
Oh... Yeah.
Of course, if you sense danger,
contact me right away. Okay?
I'm home!
That's a relief. Nothing on the first day.
Like nothing ever happened...
To think we were fighting for our lives...
It doesn't feel real.
I tried to live out every day normally.
But...
Hey, where's Abukawa?
Wasn't he absent yesterday, too?
Yeah, I haven't been able to get
in touch with him for two or three days.
Huh...
The change happened slowly...
Abukawa didn't come to school
the next day, or the day after that.
Abukawa had been acting weird lately, huh?
He was hanging out with some
sketchy guys from another school.
--Hey, did you hear? They found a body
in the river, in the next town over!
--Stop it, Izumi!
A body?
Yeah, it was totally burned all over.
Some people are saying it was Abukawa!
On the day I set fire
to those beautiful flowers...
...I lost a friend.
Oh? Just you today, huh?
There's something I've got to ask you.
You must know why I chose the costume
as my power--what I was thinking.
Hmm... Do I?
Don't avoid the question!
Is Elena keeping you quiet somehow?
If she were to hear that,
I think she might get angry.
What'll you do if you know?
For you humans, there are some
things that are better left forgotten.
I don't care.
I don't care! Just tell me!
What are you going to do? Do you want
to quit this coin-gathering game?
You got pulled into it.
If you quit, nobody can blame you,
and it won't hurt anyone.
They might be happy, actually.
Even your nice freckled girl.
You could just relax
and forget about all this fuss.
If you've got coins, I'll take them.
In return, I can put you
back to your original form.
"We are not monsters, we are humans!"
"We are humans, and we are here
to end this meaningless game."
That is what she said.
And he said, "I want to make idiots,
like my friends here, happy."
"They're important to me, see?"
Both of them might have been
taking this game too lightly.
But both of them were striving
for something, in their own ways.
Some of the things they did were unforgivable,
but they just wanted things
to be a little better.
It must be so... For her, and for Abukawa.
What are you--
Yeah, you just keep looking
down on us like that!
You look like a human, but you
don't have feelings like us, do you?
I can't let it go!
I'm going to end this terrible game
as soon as I possibly can!
If that means I need to collect 100 coins
before anyone else, then that is what I'll do!
I'm going to take back my lost memories
and the normal lives Clair and I once had!
Do as you please.
However, you are mistaken about one thing.
I am indeed the source
from which these evils came...
But the game is not what we imagined
it would be--it's on its own path.
We...?
I can't stop it at this point.
It's become a process of nature.
And you still want to
see it through to the end...
I am prepared.
Well then, what more is there to say.
As long as I get my companions back,
I'll be satisfied.
I'll be back.
Did Abukawa notice I was there?
Why was he with them?
No, it doesn't matter
what kind of person he was--
my crimes won't disappear.
Nobody will be able to see us here.
You have some business with me, don't you?
I heard what you said.
But I don't care about collecting coins anymore.
I've come to get revenge for Madoka.
There's something I want to ask you, too!
That group was all I had.
I believed that Madoka could change the world.
And you killed him.
Five of us died in the forest,
and those that survived made it down off
that mountain because Madoka died for us.
I'm the only one left.
Where is the girl with the freckles?
I know. This guy probably
doesn't have any power by himself.
He needs to have the girl
inside him to gain power.
She did it... She killed them!
The fire in the forest,
your friends getting burned to death...
I did that!
Do you know a high school student named Abukawa?
He should have been one of your friends!
Tell me! Why was he with you?
Why did he join a group
that could kill so easily?
Abukawa wasn't like that!
He was kind! He was just!
The Abukawa I knew was not like that!
So... You didn't know
anything about him, did you?
Everyone is two-faced.
Abukawa was a good friend of ours.
He too died trying to save our friends.
I'm sure Madoka seemed like
the devil to you, too...
...but to me, he was hope.
Kill me.
Answer it.
Hello?
Shuichi? Where are you?
--Can we meet up? I need to talk to you.
--It was clear when we fought.
You can't kill.
Is someone there?!
Shuichi!
So, she did it after all.
What's going on?! Shuichi!
--Clair. It's okay.
--Revenge... For Madoka...
It's over.
Huh?
I know. I'm not the
main character in this story.
But...
I'm going to finish it myself.
For... Madoka...
Bare feet sure do hurt.
But it feels good. You really feel alive.
Humans are amazing. It's just like you said.
An alien?
Yes, my ship crashed
and my friends were flung all over.
Also, this isn't what I actually look like.
What do I actually look like?
It's been so long, I forgot.
Hey, don't you want to look
for those friends of yours?
I found one!
Mmm... I don't really feel like it.
My friends are boring.
They're all completely jaded at this point.
Eternal life sounds good,
but you could also say we gave up
our attachment to life, to evolving.
Can you really call that living?
Also, it's just kind of a pain in the ass.
Still, you should look for them.
Huh...
You'll be lonely by yourself.
What was that sound?
Was that the feeling of loneliness?
No! You're just hungry.
I see...
The sensation of consuming food
on an exceedingly unhygienic planet
that is covered with germs and microbes.
Come on, quit it.
Just kidding. It's delicious.
It makes you feel alive.
Thank you! Please allow me
to express my gratitude.
That's okay.
I'm pretty good at body upgrades!
How would you like
to shoot lasers out of your eyes?
I wouldn't.
No need to hold back. I can grant any wish!
Oh, I've got an idea! You don't want
to look for them yourself, right?
Yeah...?
Why don't you get people to help you?
This looks like coins here on earth, right?
You could put a vending machine here
and when someone puts a coin in,
you grant their wish!
Isn't that an interesting idea?
Yeah, it is. Why don't
we start with your wish, then?
Huh?
You were the first one to find a coin for me.
Honoka. I want to make your wish come true.
Is this the future you wanted?
"Hotel Mythos"
Your friends?
Yeah, my friends. If I tell them
about you, I'm sure they'll help.
That's fine. I'm not too
good around people, though.
Look!
It's okay, they're all friendly.
Yes, humans are amazing.
They are so kind... So ruthless...
Look at this. Did we find it?
Is this where it crashed?
Look for the ship!
Stop. I can't allow anyone to take these coins.
Huh?!
I'll have to ask you to leave.
What should we do?
He's alone.
Let's kill him.
Yeah.
Good. I was going to kill you anyway.
It's nice to know you're evil.
Even now, it pains me
slightly to kill good people.
This is my story. A story about my crimes...
I won't let anyone stop me.
The ending is written.
Right, Honoka?
"Episode 12: Where the Promise Was Made"